caliroots.com 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy - Caliroots

##  Customer Service 

  *  Privacy Policy 
  *  How to order 
  *  Terms 
  *  FAQ 
  *  Returns 
  *  How to measure 
  *  Contact 
  *  Work at Caliroots 
  *  Press & partners 

At Caliroots, we protect your personal privacy and continuously work to ensure that your personal data is protected when using our services.

This privacy policy explains how we collect and use your personal data. It also describes your rights and how you can exercise them. It is important that you read and understand the privacy policy and feel confident in our processing of your personal data. You are always welcome to contact us with any questions (you will find contact information at the bottom of this document).

The table below will help you navigate to those sections of particular interest to you.

1\. What is personal data?  
2\. What is personal data processing?  
3\. Who is responsible for the personal data collected by Caliroots?  
4\. When do we process your personal data and what type of personal data do we process?  
5\. Why do we process data about you?  
6\. Legal basis for processing personal data  
7\. Profiling  
8\. How long do we store your data?  
9\. Sharing of personal data  
10\. How do we protect your personal data?  
11\. Your rights  
12\. Cookies  
13\. Contact information

## 1\. What is personal data?

Personal data is all information that can be directly or indirectly attributed to a natural, now living person. For example, images and sound recordings that are processed in computers can be personal data even if no names are mentioned. Encrypted data and different types of electronic identities (such as IP numbers) are personal data, if they can be linked to natural persons.  

## 2\. What is personal data processing?

Processing of personal data is everything that happens to the personal data. Every action taken with personal data is processing, regardless of whether it is performed automatically or not. Examples of usual processing are collection, registration, structuring, organising, storing, processing, transfer and erasure.  

## 3\. Who is responsible for the personal data that is collected by Caliroots?

Californian Roots AB, Reg. No. 556656-7086, Hornsbruksgatan 28, 117 34 Stockholm, is data controller for the company's processing of personal data and intends to process all personal data in accordance with applicable law (General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679).  

## 4\. When do we process your personal data and what type of personal data do we process?

**4.1 For Caliroots customers**  
Information collected in connection with a purchase is required in order for you, as a consumer, to enter into a contract with Caliroots and to enable us to fulfil our obligations relating to a purchase.  
_The data we process is:_

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * Payment details
  * Customer number
  * IP address
  * Details of your purchases
  * Information on how you use the Caliroots website

**4.2 For those who have an account at Caliroots**  
If you have an account at Caliroots, we collect the personal data you provide at account registration and also we continuously collect while you have the Caliroots account.  
_The data we process is:_

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Customer number
  * IP address
  * Details of your purchases
  * Information on how you use the Caliroots website

**4.3 For those who subscribe to the Caliroots newsletter**  
We work hard to ensure that subscribers to the Caliroots newsletter receive as interesting and relevant information/offers as possible.   
_The data we process is:_

  * Email address
  * IP address
  * Information on how you use the Caliroots website
  * How you interact with our newsletters (the type of products and offers you find relevant)
  * Details of your purchases

**4.4 For those who participate in our raffles**  
At special product releases we run so-called raffles, where a limited number of people are offered the opportunity to purchase the product.  
_The data we process in those cases is:_

  * Email address  

## 5\. Why do we process data about you?

The personal data we process at Caliroots for you as a customer of ours are processed primarily in order to:

  * Fulfil our obligations to you as a customer. For example, complete goods purchases, invoice and provide support.
  * Fulfil shipping and warranty obligations.
  * Offer general customer care and customer service (e.g. answer questions and correct incorrect data).
  * Manage the customer relationship and provide our services.
  * Improve and develop our services, products and functions.
  * Conduct market research with the possibility of influencing offers and services.
  * Prevent the abuse of, or inappropriate use of, our services.
  * Fulfil obligations regarding competitions.
  * Comply with applicable legislation.
  * Administer and manage your personal account with Caliroots.

Personal data for newsletter subscribers may, in addition to the above, be processed in order to:

  * Provide information and customised marketing on the website, by email or by text message.
  * Enable communication with you as Subscriber, via email or text message.  

## 6\. Legal basis for processing personal data

This section describes the legal grounds and considerations upon which Caliroots bases the processing of your personal data.

Your personal data is processed, among other things, in order to fulfil an agreement with you as a customer, for example, to carry out goods purchases. It may be that the processing of your personal data is supported by consent from you. Your consent must be voluntary, specific, informed and involve unambiguous consent in order for it to apply as a legal ground. We collect consent from you as a newsletter subscriber so that we can manage tasks and obtain information about your purchases. Further, your behaviour is stored on our website, your interest in our offers and products, as well as your interaction with Caliroots. This is in order to fulfil our commitment to providing you with personal offers and the goal of providing you with an experience that is customised specifically for you.

Some of the processing of personal data that we perform is based on a so-called balance of interest. This applies, for example, to the processing we carry out so that we can send relevant offers to you. This may involve a limited segmentation of customers based, for example, on purchasing behaviour.

Caliroots does not process sensitive personal data based on balance of interest.

In some cases, Caliroots may have a legal obligation to process your personal data. This applies, for example, to the processing of personal data that we carry out so that we can meet the requirements of the Accounting Act.  

## 7\. Profiling

For subscribers to the Caliroots newsletter, we may process your personal data through profiling. This means that, based on how you use our website, the products and offers in which you have shown interest, with which of our newsletters you have interacted, as well as information about purchasing, we can provide a relevant shopping experience for you as a user and we can provide offers we think are suitable for you.

You may object to this kind of processing of your personal data at any time. You do this by contacting [privacy@caliroots.com](mailto:privacy@caliroots.com). Once we receive your notification, the processing of your personal data through profiling will stop.  

## 8\. How long do we store your data?

Caliroots stores your personal data for as long as the need exists to be able to fulfil the tasks for which they were collected. In some cases we may store the data longer if necessary to comply with statutory requirements or to safeguard Caliroots' legal interests.

**For you as a customer**  
Caliroots stores your data for a maximum of 24 months (two years) after you as a customer last interacted with us (conducted a purchase or other contact with us).

**For you as an account holder**  
We store your data for as long as you have an account with Caliroots.  

## 9\. Sharing of personal data

Caliroots may disclose personal data to third parties. Examples of occasions when data may be forwarded to third parties is to a shipper in connection with the delivery of goods or a media agency for distribution of marketing.

Caliroots may disclose your personal data if it is necessary to comply with applicable laws or government requirements, to safeguard Caliroots' legal interests or to detect, prevent or pay regard to fraud and other security or technical issues.

Caliroots aims to only store personal data within the EU/EEA. However, if personal data were to be transferred to a country outside the EU/EEA, Caliroots ensures that the personal data are still protected in accordance with the laws and regulations governing the transfer of personal data to countries outside the EU/EEA.  

## 10\. How do we protect your personal data?

At Caliroots, we have taken technical and organisational measures to protect your data from unauthorised access, manipulation and loss. We continually adapt our security measures in accordance with the progress and development that is taking place in this area.

Only those persons who actually need to process your personal data in order to fulfil our stated purposes have access to them.

In the event of any personal data incidents, Caliroots undertakes to report this to the responsible regulatory authority (Data Inspection Board) without undue delay and within 72 hours of becoming aware of the incident. If such notification cannot be made within 72 hours, Caliroots will state the reasons for the delay in the notification and information will be given in batches without further undue delay.

Caliroots undertakes to inform you as soon as possible if you have been affected by a personal data incident and take the necessary precautions.  

## 11\. Your rights

Caliroots is responsible for the processing of your personal data in accordance with applicable laws and, at your request or on our own initiative, we will correct, anonymise, erase or supplement data that is found to be incorrect, incomplete or misleading.

**You have the right to request:**

  1. _Access to your personal data_  
You are entitled to request a register extract of the personal data that is registered about you and the processing we perform regarding your personal data. In the register extract you also have the right to receive information on where the data has been obtained if the personal data was not collected from you, the existence of automated decision making (including profiling) and the predicted period for which the data will be stored, or the criteria used to determine this period.  
 
  2. _Correction of your personal data_  
At your request we will correct any incorrect or incomplete information we process about you as quickly as possible.   
 
  3. _Erasure of your personal data_  
You are entitled to request that your personal data is removed. A prerequisite for this, however, is that they are no longer necessary for the purpose for which they were collected. Legal requirements may also exist that we cannot immediately delete your personal data in, for example, accounting and tax legislation. We will then end the processing that is done for purposes other than complying with the legislation.   
 
  4. _Restriction to processing_  
This means that your personal data is marked so that they can only be processed for certain limited purposes. For example, you may request a restriction when you believe your data is incorrect and you have requested a correction in accordance with the section _"Correction of your personal data"_ above. While the accuracy of the data is investigated, processing will be restricted.

If Caliroots has disclosed your information to third parties, we will notify you of any corrections or erasure of data as well as restriction on data processing.

If your personal data is stored by Caliroots, you are entitled to data portability. This means that, under certain conditions, you may request to remove and transfer your personal data in a structured, widely used and machine-readable format to another data controller.

If Caliroots' personal data processing is performed on the basis of a balance of interests, you are entitled to object to this. In the event of an objection, Caliroots will only continue processing if there are legitimate reasons for processing that outweigh your interests. Caliroots bears the burden of proof as to whether such reasons exist.

As a registered person, you are entitled to file any complaints regarding the processing of your personal data with the Data Inspection Board.   

## 12\. Cookies

The cookies we use at Caliroots are there to improve the services we offer. Some of our services need cookies to work properly, while others improve the services for you. We use cookies for general analytical information regarding your use of our services and to save functional settings such as languages and other data. We also use cookies to direct relevant marketing to you.

If you want, your browser or device will allow you to change the settings for the usage and scope of cookies. Go to settings in your browser or device to learn more about adjusting the settings for cookies. Examples of what you can adjust include blocking all cookies, only accepting first-party cookies, or deleting cookies when you close your browser. Bear in mind that some of our services might not work if you block or delete cookies.  

## 13\. Contact information

If you have any questions about our Privacy policy, the processing of your personal data, or if you wish to request a register extract, please contact us.

Californian Roots AB  
Hornsbruksgatan 28  
117 34 Stockholm  
Sweden

_Email:_[privacy@caliroots.com](mailto:privacy@caliroots.com)  
_Telephone:_ +46 8-720 07 97   
_Company registration number:_ 5566567086
